Got to move! Get the kids!
We gotta get home!
Crazy woman.
Ah, speak of the devil.
How'd it go? Great.
Did you get your source? Absolutely.
Good.
Dana, we're gonna put Rosenblum
on your story.
Excuse me? You're short on manpower.
And you know I hate
losing to the Post.
We're not gonna lose
to the Post.
Don't get me started
on the Journal.
We're not gonna lose
to the Journal.
Especially not with my help.
What are you gonna do? I got Sandberg.
You actually talked to him?
We're sitting down next week. When?
I wanna hear everything you got
by Monday's page-one meeting.
Meantime,
you two exchange notes.
When next week? It's not set yet.
Oh. Okay, so all of this
is predicated
on a meeting
you don't actually have.
No, no, I said it's not set
yet, but next week.
No, you said it wasn't set yet.
No, I said it's not set, until...
Are you for real? No. Yes.
Uh, Dana? He just says "Sandberg,"
and suddenly he's on my story? Dana.
Because I've come to you
a thousand times
and it's never been that easy.Yeah.
When you sit down with him,
tell him I said hi.
Dana. Because I just had that meeting
that you think you're gonna get.Dana. Dana.
What?
Shit.
Hang on a minute. It's me.
I heard what happened.
Rosenblum is telling everybody
he's on your story now.
Oh, I can't stand
his little smug ass.
Why you still breastfeeding?
Jordan's 1.
Because the World Health
Organization recommends it
for up to two years and beyond.
Kid's got a mouth
full of teeth, D.
He's gonna be able to spell
"milk" pretty soon.
Doesn't it hurt?
It's a good way
for us to stay close.
How you doing? My blouse is almost dry.
I'm not asking
about your blouse.
Please don't isolate yourself.
I'm not isolated,
we're talking right now.
You know what I mean, D.
You work, you go home.
That's all you ever do.
I'm a single mother.
All right.
You're not gonna talk to me,
you better talk to someone. I am fine.
I don't think you're fine.
I would tell you if I wasn't.
Now, if you will excuse me,
I have to go make sure little
Rosenblum stays off my story.
How you doing, Manny? Evening, Ms. Canedy.
Saw little man earlier.
Not so little anymore.
Who are you telling?
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
How is he? Taking his nap.
Still?
Hope he's not coming down
with something.
No. No, that boy ran wild
in the park.
I had to pry him away. Thank you, Kaleisha.
You should go on home.
Okay, let me finish up,
and I'll see you
tomorrow, all right? Okay.
Here I come.
Tell him everything, Ma.
"Dear Jordan,"
I want you to know that it's
all right for boys to cry.
Sometimes crying can release
a lot of pain and stress.
"It has nothing to do
with your manhood."
Your father wrote that.
He wrote this whole thing.
Just for you.
I thought you should hear it
because...
well, you cry a lot.
Dear Jordan,
if you are reading this
it means that we got through
the sorrowful years somehow,
and that you are old enough
to understand
all that I am about to tell you.
The first time I saw your
father, Charles Monroe King,
was in the living room
of the house where I grew up.
It was the spring of 1998.
And I was visiting your
grandfather for this birthday.
So, baby, how's Dwayne doing?
Mike, come on. Mama,
I told you, we broke up.
Well, flames rekindle.
Look at your brother.
Remember when he
and Charlene fell out?
Yeah. I'm shocked
she took him back.
Well, you never know.
Did you call him?
Now, why would I do that?
You're the one who said
he's so perfect. Mommy.
Works on Wall Street.Ma.
Ivy League. I know.
Speaks Italian.
We are not getting back
together, okay?
It's over. You never know.
No, Mom.
Some things you do know.
Well, well, well.
Oops. Sorry.
Grace?
Bless us, oh, Lord,
for these gifts we're about
to receive from thy bounty
through Christ our Lord. Amen.
Amen.Amen.
Amen.
Who's smoking reefer out here?
Shit.
Y'all know this house
is downwind, right?
You want a hit? You know I don't smoke.
You can't think
when you're high.
Might help you relax. I'm relaxed.
You think I need to relax?
What? Do you? Girl, yes.
Okay, maybe I'm a little type A.A little?
They stress me out.
Why you think
I'm staying at a hotel?
Same reason we out here
getting high.
I just don't understand how she
stays with him all these years.
She loves him. That is not love. It's fear.
She's scared to end up alone.
Is that how it is, Mike?
Huh?
Is that how it is being married?
Is what how it is?
Aren't you scared
you're gonna end up alone?
No, not really.
Shit, sometimes I wish
she would leave me alone.
But are you happy? Yeah.
We fight and shit, but yeah.
See, there's hope.
Now I just gotta find
the right guy.
Good luck.
Men are luxuries.
Not necessities.
Damn.Damn.
I'm not playing.
Apparently not.
It's cold,
I'll see y'all inside.
All right.
Hi.Hi.
I'm a friend of your father's.
Oh.
Are you Dana or Gwen? Dana.
The journalist.
And you are?
Oh. I'm, uh, First Sergeant
Charles King, at your service.
Oh. You're a soldier. Yes, ma'am.
Your father was my drill
sergeant back in the day.
I just came by
to hang this for him.
Early birthday present.
761st Tank Battalion.
Some of the bravest men
to fight in World War II.
Me and your dad are tankers,
so we share a mutual admiration.
What do you think about it?
It's beautiful.
Is that pointillism?
Yes, ma'am, it is.
You know, like Georges Seurat.
Takes a bit more time,
but I think it's worth it.
You drew that? Yes, ma'am.
Technically, it's a painting.
But I won't hold it against you.
You know, sarge talks
about you a lot.
Does he? Nonstop. All three of you.
You're his pride and joy.
Is he here? Yes, ma'am.
He's out on the porch.
I told him to wait there
while I finished hanging this.
Excuse me real quick.
Morning, Daddy. Oh, good morning.
Happy birthday.Oh...
I know it's not till tomorrow,
but these are cigars,
so don't let Mommy see them.
Thank you, pumpkin.
So your friend in there.
He finish putting
my picture up yet?
Not yet.
But you're gonna love it.
He's, uh, talented, isn't he?
And good looking.
Did Gwen meet him yet?
No, she's been out
with your mom all morning.
Oh...
Just tell him you forgot
something at your hotel,
your sister
wants to borrow your car.
Daddy. I'm just trying to help.
Don't.
Okay.
Excuse me? Hi.
Can I ask you a favor?
I left my cell phone
back at my hotel,
and my sister needs to borrow
my car when she gets back.
Would you mind giving me a ride?
You mind if I turn on the radio?
No, sure.
What kind of music do you like?
There should be a CD in there.
Oldies? Yeah, that's the Spinners.
You don't talk much, do you? Yeah, I do.
I mean,
when I got something to say.
Okay.
So my dad
was your drill sergeant?
Yes, ma'am.
He taught me
how to be a soldier.
I'm lucky I met him.
Both of your folks.
They've been there for me.
Good.
Go! You want an invite?
Sorry.
You can take the girl
out of the city...
you can't take the city
out of the girl.
You know I'm a journalist,
so I have to ask.
My parents have been there
for you how?
I'm going through a divorce.
Oh.
I'm sorry. Eh, don't be.
Your mom's a great listener,
and Pop always invites me over
to watch ball games.
Pop? Yes, ma'am.
I mean, don't get me wrong,
I love my parents,
but I don't think I would have
made it through without yours.
Hmm.
Why do you seem so surprised?
You didn't grow up with them.
What about you? What about me?
You seeing someone?
I'm surprised my parents
didn't tell you
since you all talk so much.
I'm single. Recently.
Hey, listen, I'm supposed to go
to the house tomorrow
for the barbeque.
I could pick you up
on my way if you want.
Yeah, that'd be great.
How's 0900?
Early.
That's perfect.
No housekeeping.
Come back later.
It's Charles King.
Who?
First Sergeant Charles King. Oh, shit.
Uh, what-what time is it?
Uh, 49.
I asked for a wake-up call,
I'm so sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I'll be right out.
I-it's okay. Take your time.
I won't be long. Sh...!
I promise.
Whenever you're ready,
I'll be here.
Shit! Shit!
I'm so sorry. It was worth the wait.
Um, hi.Hi.
Are you hungry? I could eat.
All right. After you.
So, what made you join the Army?
The discipline. The travel.
And I love my country,
so I always wanted to serve.
Plus, the camo
just brings out my eyes.
It's a tough way
to make a living.
Yes, ma'am, it is.
You know you don't
have to call me ma'am.
I know. I don't want to either.
Belgian waffle.
Side of hash browns.
Thank you.And...
I've got scrambled
egg whites and oatmeal.
Perfect. Got you a
little extra brown sugar.
You sure you don't want
some fruit or something?
No, thank you.
I'm fine. Thanks, ma'am.
You let me know
if you need anything.
Excuse me. Hi.Hi.
I'm gonna need some hot sauce
for those hash browns
and a little warm up, please. Sure thing.
So how long
have you been in the Army?
Just one second, I'm sorry.
All right, thank you.
Uh, it's been 11 years.
I plan on doing another nine
and hopefully retiring
a Sergeant Major.
Then I want to focus on my art.
Who's your favorite artist?
You ask a lot of questions.
Occupational hazard.Mm.
Well, if you must know,
I have two.
Georges Seurat?
Yeah.
And Claude Monet.
You heard of him?
Of course.
He's my number one.
I mean, I mess around a bit with
pointillism but Monet's style?
I mean, who's messing with him?
You, um,
got a little bit right...
Oh.Some right here.
Other side.
Just... All right,
you smudged it. Let me...
You mind? Uh... No.
Got a little bit. Yep.
Thanks.
Mm-hm.
You know, I saw some of Monet's
work at the Met in New York.
I've never been to New York.
It's so different when you can
see the brushstrokes up close.
And I've actually never seen
a real Monet in person.
Mm.
You should get up there
sometime.
To see the painting?
Maybe I will.
Ooh! Look at that.
Yeah, baby.
Hey. Hey, Charles!
Hey, come on over
and meet First Sergeant King.
Gentlemen. Just call them fellas.
Why in the world would anybody
want to do that?
I don't understand.
You know what I'm saying?
Oh, what? It's not.
You're getting very upset.
Well, I thought men were
luxuries, not necessities.
You just wanna stand there
or you gonna come help me?
You're lucky you saw him first.
Appreciate you coming by, son.
I appreciate the food.
Anytime.Yeah.
We'll see you again soon, hon.
Okay? Yes. Of course.
You leaving already? I am. Yes, ma'am.
I mean, yes, I am. Are you sure?
I was just about
to put out dessert.
I wish that I could. Fresh apple pie.
I got a phone date
with my daughter.
Oh.
Yeah, she lives in Texas
with her mother,
and I gotta catch her
before she goes to sleep.
Of course.
Well, if you're ever in New York
and wanna see that Monet,
look me up.
Will do.
Now, take care. You too.
What?
Hello?
Hi, can I speak to Dana, please?
This is she. Hey.
This is First Sergeant
Charles King.
Oh.
Hello, Charles.
My dad told me
he gave you my number.
Three weeks ago.
Yeah. Um...
Is now a good time to talk?
Mm...
I am kind of in the middle
of something.
Oh, okay, I can call you back.
No. No, that's fine.
I have a few minutes.
Listen, Dana, I would have
called you sooner.
But...
I just... I wanna be honest
and my divorce just got final.
I don't want to make things
harder for you, Charles.
No, but you're not. You're not.
That's exactly why
I'm calling you right now.
You've got your daughter
to think about.
And I'm always gonna be
thinking about her.
You know, it's not gonna change.
But I just want you to know
that you don't have anything
to worry about.
I promise.
Fair enough.
Hello?
Dana, I want you to know
I've been thinking about you.
A lot.
Well, you have had three weeks.
Okay, okay,
let's blow them out. Ready?
Yay!
Okay, now,
let's get all sugared up.
Here we go.
Okay.
All right, time out.
Mommy needs a little break.
Peek-a-boo, Daddy!
What are you talking about?
What? Okay.
What are you looking at?
What are you saying, silly boy?
Peek-a-boo, Daddy!
Hello?
Hey, it's Charles.
How you doing?
Better now.
There's barely any Black people,
let alone Black women.
No second chances if I mess up.
It's like
I'm the standard bearer
for every other Black person
who wants to work there.
I understand that.
But you do love what you do,
right?
It's the New York Times.
Of course I love it.
For a journalist,
that's the dream come true.
It's the only time I hate New
York, when it's hot and muggy.
New York is not hot.
Iraq, now, that's hot.
You've been to Iraq?
Kuwait too. Desert Storm.
Wow, was it bad?
Bad enough.
Listen, can I
call you back later?
I got a meeting with the brass
in a few,
and I do not want to be late.
Yeah, of course.
Call me tomorrow.
All right, bye.
Bye.
Hang up.
You hang up.
No, you hang up.
Are we really doing this
right now?
I guess we are.
Okay.
Are you gonna hang up the phone?
Bye.
So do you think you'll want
more kids?
Definitely.
I always wanted a big family.
How's your daughter handling it?
Christina? She's great.
Beautiful. She listens. Smart.
Lot smarter than me,
I'll tell you that.
Hold on one second.
Um...
You know, it was, uh...
It was stressful.
It was stressful for everybody.
Well, how did you handle it?
How did I handle it?
It was, um...
I felt like a failure.
Tried to make it work.
But, you know, we were young.
We were kids
trying to figure it out and...
you know, we both were to blame,
you know, so...
It hurt.
Well, I'm sorry you were hurt.
Hey, no, it's...
You know, I'm doing good.
And I love being a father.
You know, one of the best things
that ever happened to me.
And if I didn't go through that,
I wouldn't be talking to you,
so...
Sometimes after dinner,
my father would announce
he was going to buy milk.
I never understood how my mom
could just sit there
with her head down.
She knew he was
having an affair.
Hell, the whole town did.
One night, I came down
with this terrible flu,
and my mom had to borrow
the neighbor's car
to take me to the hospital.
And I just remember lying there
on that back seat, delirious.
When I lifted my head up,
I saw we were driving around
a parking lot of a bar
on the base.
How old were you? I was 7.
She was looking for his car.
Did she ever find it? No.
He used to say
that she trapped him
by getting pregnant with me.
She was just as trapped
as he was.
Wow.
How'd that make you feel?
Now, see... Mm-mm.
You are all up in my business.
Trying to get me all open.
Well, sounds a little too late
for that.
What did you say?
You heard me.
No, I'm just playing.
Enough about me.
So, what do you do?
When you're not turning
young men into soldiers.
Well, if I'm not drawing
or painting...
probably in the gym.
Okay. I like the gym too.
For the massages, and the little
smoothies at the juice bar.
Are you telling me you go to
the gym and you don't work out?
Well, I'm not exactly
the workout type.
But I stay active.
It's a walking city.
Well, the massages
or juices, smoothies, all that,
whatever it is you're doing...
it's working.
I think you are beautiful.
So you like this guy or not?
I can't. He's a soldier.
My dad was a soldier.
It's not like he walks around
in uniform all the time.
That shit would be hot though,
boo-boo.
Oh, girl!
And he's divorced.
And he has
a 9-year-old daughter.
So? Is he a good dad?
He seems like it.
I don't know. I don't know.
He is not exactly my type.
Look, you said he was nice,
right?
Mm-hm.
And he's cute too? God, yes.
So, what's your problem?
Are you too good for him?
You little bougie bitch.
I barely know him.
We've only talked on the phone.
If you decide to let him visit,
don't shave your legs.
What? I know you.
There is no way you would ever
sleep with a guy,
at least not the first time,
without exfoliating,
moisturizing, and shaving.
God, it's true.
Same.
Sorry I can't come pick you up.
Don't worry about it.
I know you got work.
If you get lucky with traffic,
you should be here about30.
You know, I could
just stay in a hotel.
It's not a problem.
Of course not. Don't be silly.
I mean, unless... Well,
do you wanna stay at a hotel?
No. No, I'm good.
Good. Okay, good.
Oh, and by the way,
that cab ride from LaGuardia
shouldn't cost you
more than 30 bucks.
I usually tip
if he helps me with my bags.
And don't let him take
the Queensboro Bridge.
Okay, general.
Hopefully, all my training
and the tank battles
I survived in Iraq
have prepared me enough
for New York City.
As you were, Negro.
And if I don't make it... Oh, God.
I want you to know that I tried.
Can you call my mama for me and
just tell her that I love her?
Charles, you can stop now.
Guess what.
Huh?
Guess. What?
Chicken butt.
You are so corny.
Get off the phone!
Hey, are you there?
Yes, ma'am. I'm right here.
I'm sorry, Manny.
No problem, Ms. Canedy.
Your guest has arrived.
Do you want me to send him up?
Yes, please.
I left the key for him.
Yes, ma'am, I got it right here.
Can you put him on real quick?
Sure. She wants to talk to you.
Hey, just wanna let you know
that I made it in safe.
Mission accomplished.
Happy to hear.
So I'm not gonna be home
for another couple hours.
Yeah, that's fine.
I got my sketchbook with me,
so handle your work.Okay.
Help yourself to anything
in the fridge.
I'll do that. See you later? It's him.
Can you put Manny back on? Sure. Hold on.
Yes, ma'am.
Manny, it's his first time
in New York,
help him if he needs anything. Yes, ma'am.
Can you see if he has on
kind of worn-out sneakers?
Probably dirty? Yes, ma'am.
Okay. You can send him up. All right.
She says you can go on up.
All right, perfect.
Thanks, man. You got it.
He there?
Mm-hm.
What are you doing?
Get out of here!
No! I have too much work to do.
Work, shmerk! Go get some!
Here you go.
Ms. Canedy.Manny.
Hey, you.
How was your day?
It was good.
How was your flight?
Welcome home.
Mm.
You smell good. Thank you.
I got something for you.
This is for you.
Oh, my God.
You like it?
I do.
I really tried to imagine you
in my head.
What? I'm lying.
I used that photo over there. Oh, my God.
Glad you like it.
So I know you just got here,
but we should probably talk
about sleeping arrangements.
I have a sofa bed.
It's pretty comfortable.
That's fine.
I have no problem
sleeping on the couch.
Why you look nervous?
What did you think
I was gonna say?
I don't look nervous.
I just didn't want to set up
any unrealistic expectations.
Mm-hm. Well, I expect
to have a good time.
I'm not worried.
I'll be with you.
Okay. Have we decided? We have. Uh...
I'm ready. Are you? Yeah.
What is that? Olive oil.
I'll have the linguini
with clam sauce, please,
and a caprese salad to start.Absolutely.
And for you, sir? I'll
have the Caesar salad.
That's it?
I'm sorry, can you give us
one minute?
Of course. Thank you.
What?
You can get
a Caesar salad anywhere.
Try the pasta. That's a lot of carbs.
You eat mess hall food all day.
Come on.
How do you know
what I like to eat? Hmm?
Well, at least get some grilled
chicken in it or something.
Okay.
I really am glad you're here.
I just want you to enjoy
your weekend and a have good...
You taste like oregano.
What kind of theater is that?
That's an off-Broadway theater.
So we're near Broadway.No.
See, there's off-Broadway,
and there's off-off-Broadway.
Okay, so is there anything
actually on Broadway?
Yes, but it's not
about the street.
It's all about the size
of the house.
The house? How many seats there are.
In the house? Yes.
Okay. In a theater house.Yes.
Just like I thought.
Charles, please.
I appreciate the manners,
but you can't keep walking
on the outside of the sidewalk.
It's New York.
There are too many people.
I'm sorry. I just can't help it.
Just... It's a force of habit.
You know what?
No, I'm sorry. Thank you.
The world needs more gentlemen.
That's an off-off-Broadway kiss.
That's an off-Broadway kiss.
And this is...
Broadway.
And the Tony Award
for best kiss goes to...
No, hold on a second.
Who the hell is Tony?
Easy.
Uh, I'm gonna go freshen up
really quick.
There's water and stuff
in the fridge,
so help yourself to whatever.Okay.
She's so fine.
No.
Do you need anything?
Uh, yeah, maybe just a couple
extra pillows and a blanket.
That red wine got me sleepy.
I was thinking maybe you could
sleep on one side of the bed.
If you want.
Yeah. Yeah, that'd be cool.
We should stop.
Huh?
Yeah, sorry. Uh...
It's all that oregano.
Good night.
Who travels
with exercise equipment?
I do.
You slept good. I slept well.
You slept well.
Now, you need
to put all that away.
I have not had my coffee yet.
I remembered.
You like it black, right?
Yes, I do.
All right, so I'm gonna
need you to get up,
get in the shower, get dressed,
then we'll go for a run.
But I wanna see more
of your city. Okay?
And I wanna see
more of your city.
I'll take your state,
your zip code.
I wanna see your area code.
I wanna see your social
security number.
I wanna see your passport,
your military ID,
your blood type.
Show it all to me.
Oh, my God! I wanna see it all!
Mmm! Mm-hm.
Mm-hm. I told you.
You really trying to corrupt me.
You know you like it.
So when are you
gonna show me this Monet?
Saving the best for last.
You know, I can't show you
the whole city in one weekend.
Then I guess I gotta come back.
Wait. What? What?
I have to take a shower. Now?
Yes, now. Because. No, no, why?
No.No.
I'll be right back.
I'll keep that in mind.
Close the drapes.
I got you.
Slow down.
You like it?
I love it.
It's so beautiful.
Thank you.
What?
What are you doing up before me?
We've only got four days,
soldier.
It's Christmas time in New York.
Up and at them.
Are you done yet?
Yeah.
Well, come on out. Let me see.
Charles, get out here, please.
Oh, yes.
I-I don't know.
Let's try the blazer. Come on.
I look like
somebody's accountant.
Mm-hm. A fine one.
And do you know how expensive
these clothes are?
It's a Christmas gift.
No, I can't let you do that. I want to.
I know you don't care
about clothes.
Because clothes
don't make the man, baby.
But the man can make
the clothes, baby.
Besides, you work hard.
You deserve more than just
baggy jeans and T-shirts.
I like my jeans.Okay.
Well, what about
the grandpa sneakers?
Grandpa?
The only place you should be
wearing those to is the gym.
They're practical
and comfortable.
And those aren't? Come on, now.
Don't act like
you don't like it.
Look at you. Smile. See?
Fine.
I'm keeping my sneakers,
I'm paying for half.
Charles! Half!
Baby. Hmm?
I want you to be my girlfriend.
What?
I want you to be my lady.
Like, officially.
What do you mean,
like, go steady?
You know exactly what that means.
Heh.
That's funny? No. It's just...
It's just what? We're grown.
Yeah. We're grown enough
to commit to one another.
Charles.
Don't say my name like that.
Can we talk about this later?
I want to now.
We have guests. They can wait.
Please?
- Merry Christmas!- Hi.
Merry Christmas!
However, I don't want her hurt.
I don't want her hurt. No, no.
That's not my intention at all.
I know it's not your intentions,
but it may happen.
He actually said officially?
That's the sweetest thing I ever heard.
Oh, my God.
To die for. It is so corny.
But he can't help it.
He's military.
You can't help it.
You're falling for him.
Yeah, you're sprung, boo-boo. I am not.
I've never seen you
like this before.
Like what? Like you like him.
Of course I like him. No,
I mean, you "like" like him.
Like you really like him.
I want a drink. You want wine or...
It's Christmas, I need a drink.
I need a drink.
But you're gonna be good to her.
Yes, yes, ma'am, I am.
You said... No, no, I want Scotch.
You weren't kidding
about his ass.
You could bounce a quarter
off that thing.
'Tis the season. Ho, ho, ho.
Just tell me one thing. Hmm?
Is he good in bed?
Now, you know we wouldn't be
talking if he weren't.
Good God.
I don't want that.Yeah.
She's a good girl. She is a very good girl.
She was a...
Don't talk to me like that.
No, no, like a nice girl.
Julie? Yeah, Ms. Judy.
Yeah, she could talk.
She could talk.
So you gonna answer my question?
What question?
The one we were
talking about earlier.
Charles, you know
I care about you.
Why do we have to define
our relationship?
Because we have one. But what's the hurry?
There's no hurry. We've just
been together for six months.
I don't wanna give up my career
to follow you around
to different military bases.
Well, who said anything
about that?
And you don't even live here.
You seeing somebody else? What?
Are you seeing somebody else? No.
I'm serious.
No. I'm not.
I would never ask you to give up
your career just to follow me.
You know that, right?
Yeah, I know.
I'm not saying this is gonna be
easy, but we can make this work.
How can you be so sure?
I can't.
I can't predict
the future either,
but I know we got a shot at one.
Do you trust me?
Yeah.
Then be my girlfriend.
Officially.
I already am.
You know you could've told me
that earlier, right?
I had to make you work for it.
Now it's about to be your turn.
Lead the way.
Leave them open.
Baby.
Slow down, slow down, slow down.
Hold up.
Do you want a ride?
Now, you know you don't wanna
drive to the airport
this early in the morning.
It's freezing out.
And you could put this one
under the tree.
Another one? This is for Manny.
The doorman?
It's a Mets hat.
He's from Queens.
I didn't know you two
were friends.
We're buddies.
Oh, buddies.
Bet you didn't know
he was a marine.
No. He never mentioned it.
That's because you two
aren't buddies.
This is for you.
It's a bunch of grandpa music?
Hey, that's grown man music
right there.
Crazy woman.
Am I?
What? Crazy.
Absolutely not.
I'm gonna call you when I land. Be careful.
I will.
You know, you can leave
some of your new stuff here.
I can clear out
some closet space.
If you want.
- Hello?- Guess what.
Chicken butt.
I'm serious.
Okay, what?
We're doing a whole series
on race in America.
I'm writing one of the stories,
and they want me
to be an editor too.
This is the biggest opportunity
they've ever given me.
Hey! Congratulations.
But if I don't nail this,
my career at theTimes
will literally be over.
Woman, please. No, no, I'm not kidding.
They'll fire me.
I can't lose this job, Charles.
New York is too expensive,
and...
Stop. Listen, they picked you
because you're qualified
and you do outstanding work.
I'm proud of you.
Thank you, baby.
And I can't wait to read
what you write.
I gotta start flying to Akron
once a week
before I write anything.
Not looking forward to that.
Okay, well, just give me
a couple weeks.
Let me get my new soldiers
squared away,
and I'll see if I can fly down.
Really? Yeah.
I'd love that.
You've reached
First Sergeant Charles King.
Please leave a message
after the beep.
Hey, sweetie.
I made it back to Akron.
I think all this traveling
has got me sick.
Thank you. Thank you.
Anyways, I, uh...
I can't wait to see you.
Call me later. Bye.
You've reached
First Sergeant Charles King.
Please leave a message
after the beep.
Charles, where are you?
Starting to get worried.
Charles? Hey, baby.
Where are you? I'm at the hospital.
One of my soldiers' wives
just had a baby.
Well, I've been calling you.
I'm sorry. I had to come
to the hospital to help him.
Help him what?
Dana, he's 19 years old.
You know, he was scared.
He needed me.
Well, they don't have phones
at the hospital?
It was pretty hectic in here.
I tried,
but I couldn't get away.
Well, since when
is delivering babies
a part of your job description?
How about we both
get some sleep tonight,
and we'll talk about it
in the morning?
It is morning.
And I'm sick as a dog
and stuck in Akron, Ohio,
waiting for you.
I thought you were
in a plane crash.
I-I'm sorry.
I should've called you,
but you know
I have to be there for my men.
And what about me?
Your official girlfriend.
I haven't seen you
in two months.
Baby, it's only been six weeks.
Okay, I don't think you
understand how hurt I am.
Dana,
his wife had complications.
Well, what kind?
I don't know exactly.
So, you've been there all night
and you don't know anything?
All I know is that
she needed a C-section.
Hmm. I see.
So maybe you're the one
that's seeing someone else.
What? That why you
missed your flight?
What? No. No. No.
You wanna talk to him? He's in
the other room with his wife.
Charles,
you can get your soldiers
to say anything that you want.
Come on, Dana,
you're talking crazy.
Crazy? I have been sitting
in a hotel room for hours
waiting on you. Why would I lie?
You did not even bother
to call me
to let me know
that you're not coming.
Relax. I don't need to relax.
We're... You... I can't do this.
Goodbye.
Hey, Manny. Welcome back, Ms. Canedy.
You got a delivery earlier.
I hope you don't mind,
I put it upstairs.Thanks.
What are you doing here?
Dana, I screwed up.
And I'm sorry.
No, no, you can't just show up
like this.
We haven't spoken in weeks.
Because you won't return
my calls.
Because I didn't wanna
talk to you.
I'm sorry I didn't show up
in Akron.
You're right. I should've
called you that night.
I had no idea where you were.
Or who you were with.
I wasn't with anybody.
Dana.
Baby.
I'm... I'm not your father.
I will never be
with another woman.
I love you.
You don't love me. I do.
No, you love your men.
I'm just better looking.No. Dana.
I love you.
I might've given you
a reason to leave me, but...
I'm never gonna leave you.
I love you.
I love you too.
I'm not going anywhere.
You can trust that. Okay?
You can trust that.
Okay? Okay?
I love you so much.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
You know, it's not
a bad color on you.
Sometimes I forget
you're a soldier.
Can I ask you a question?
Have I ever been able
to stop you?
What's combat like?
My dad never talks
about Vietnam.
You never talk about Iraq.
To be honest,
I don't remember much.
Smells.
Sounds.
Training kicks in,
so it's kind of a blur.
Were you scared?
Of course I was.
Have you ever actually
killed someone?
How can you be a soldier
and believe in God?
I believe in evil too.
Protecting people
who can't protect themselves.
Hard work work! Hard work work!
And everyone's doing
another formation.
Hey! What's wrong with you, boy?
Get your ass out of the line.
What's wrong with you, boy!
Get your ass over here.
What's wrong with you?
Your ass is out of formation.
March now! March!
You know what I'm talking about?
They're sitting here, waiting.
Yes, first sarge. Wagon wheel!
Are you out of your mind? No, first sarge.
We're out in the streets,
taking fire,
you looking real weak here.
You see these guys? Yes.
They're willing to take
a bullet and die for you.
Look at them.
They're willing to die for you.
You tired? You tired? Yes, first sarge.
Keep moving your feet.
I'm gonna put you on my back.
It's no man left behind.
No man left behind, you hear me?
Yes, first sarge.
Do I need to carry you? No.
Get on my back
and I'll carry you! No!
I know you're still smoking
those cigarettes.
Yes, first sarge. You
gotta get off that stuff.
Come on. Get in my formation,
let's go.
Let's go! Work, work.
Come on, Imhoff! No more
slow asses, you feel me?
There it is. Let him hear it!
Hard work work.
Hard work work. Work work.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, sorry.
Charles? Dana.
You okay? Hey. Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
You're safe? Yes, I'm safe.
Where are you? I'm at the office.
You watching this?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Another plane has just hit
into another building.
I want you to go home
and don't leave.
Call your parents, tell them
not to leave the house.
Don't do anything till you
hear from me, got it?
Yeah. Yes, I got it. I got it! Nothing.
All right, I gotta go.Charles. Wait.
Yes? Please be careful.
You too.
Okay. All right, bye.
Hey, sweetie. How was school? Fine.
May I come in? No.
Do you wanna talk? No.
Jordan Monroe King, look at me.
Oh, my God, baby, what happened?
I got in a fight.
With who? Lance.
Oh, I'm calling the principal.
And I wanna talk
to that boy's parents.
Mom, no.
Snitches get stitches. What?
If I snitch, I'm dead.
Jordan, why were you fighting?
They called me a wigger.
A white nigger.
They say all kinds of stuff. Like what?
Like if I'm Black, how come
I'm not good at basketball?
Oh, sweetie.
They said my dad
wasn't a soldier.
They said if he's Black,
he's probably in prison.
Okay.
Come with me.
Take your coat off. Sit down.
Am I in trouble? No.
Read it.
Out loud.
"Jordan, you are
African-American."
No one can ever
take that away from you.
You will be challenged
because of your complexion
and the color of your eyes.
But let your character and deeds
shine in everything you do.
"And never forget
where you came from."
What's this?
Your dad wrote it.
He wrote everything in there
just for you.
You're old enough now,
so I want you to read it.
Every word.
Y'all know it's not my birthday.
Are y'all trying
to scam free dessert?
Well, you wouldn't let us
celebrate last year,
and I know how much you hate it
on the actual day, so...
Make a wish.
Whoa!
You guys. Open mine first.
Fine.
Is this what I think it is? Mm-hm.
If you won't let me
set you up on dates,
you should at least
have some pleasure.
I go on dates.
Three dates
and a one-night stand
in over a decade does not count.Mm-hm.
Well, do I have to plug it in? Plug it in.
And then work your way up
to the highest setting.
Slowly. Not too slowly.
You have one too? Oh, yeah.
Yeah, we all do. Better
than most boyfriends.
No, I don't know about that,
boo-boo.
Well, I do.
It's better than my husband
half the time,
I'll tell you that.
Shit, wish I could
plug his ass in.
Woof.Oh.
Oh.
Mom, what's that?
Uh...
It's a massager. For tension.
What's up?
You think we could go see
my sister in Texas soon?
Christina? Of course, baby.
We should see her more.
My dad said he wanted us
to get to know each other.
Well, we can do that. Come here.
How come you barely ever
talk about him?
Well, sometimes,
it hurts to remember.
But I think about him
all the time.
And I write about him too.
That makes me feel better.
Why don't we have
any pictures of him?
We do.
Just that one on your desk
with the balloons.
We'll put more up.
With the folded flag, like
Nana and Grandpa King have?
Well, the Army only gives those
to the family at the funeral.
We're his family. We are.
But technically, I'm not.
Your father and I
never got married.
My fellow citizens,
at this hour,
American and coalition forces
are in the early stages
of military operations
to disarm Iraq,
to free its people,
and to defend the world
from grave danger.
On my orders, coalition forces
have begun striking selected
targets of military importance
to undermine Saddam Hussein's
ability to wage war.
Hello? Hey.
Hey, oh, my God, you scared me.
I'm sorry. You okay? Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
Oh, I got your painting.
It's beautiful. I love it.
I'm glad you like it.
Baby, uh, listen. Yeah?
What's wrong?
Nothing. Nothing. What?
I got my orders for Iraq.
When do you deploy?
I don't know.
We transfer out
to Fort Irwin tomorrow.
California? Yeah.
When can I see you?
That, I don't know.
Charles, I need to talk to you.
Call me back right away.
It's an emergency.
Charles? What's wrong?
Is that gunfire?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I'm at the range.
Is everything okay?
I need to see you.
When can you come home?
Are you okay?
Yes, but I don't wanna talk
about it on the phone.
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Cease fire! Talk about what?
Can you come this weekend?
Please?
Baby, I can't just leave
like that.
Okay, well, maybe
I can come and see you.
Dana, tell me what's wrong.
I wanna have a baby.
What?
I wanna get pregnant.
Now?
Yes. Now.
Commence fire! Commence fire!
Where's all this coming from?
Because I wanna live life,
and not just report on it.
And I wanna live it with you
so please have a baby with me.
Absolutely.
Well, you don't wanna
take a second to think about it?
I'm not asking you for a puppy.
I don't need to think about it.
Are you sure?
You're the one who doesn't
sound too sure, Dana.
I just don't understand how you
can make a decision so quickly.
Because I made my mind up
a long time ago.
Well, what if I can't
get pregnant?
Marry me. What?
Marry me.
Okay.
Okay?
So is that a yes?
Charles Monroe King, yes.
I will marry you.
Cease fire! Cease fire! Cease fire!
She said yes. Sir?
I'm getting married!
Hoo-ah!
You heard that?
- What is this?- A gift.
We're going to see Dad.
Jordan, I have work.
You have school.
Mom. It's on a weekend.
It's only Washington, D.C.,
it's not that far.
Baby, give me and your auntie
a minute, please.
Good luck.
You have no right to do this,
Miriam.
The hell I don't.
He's my godson. I love him too.
Who's paying for this? It's taken care of.
So this was your idea? No. Jordan's.
He e-mailed me.
He needs this trip.
You both do.
Hey.
Listen, it's not like Charles
left you with nothing.
We both know that little man
in there is special.
And he needs you right now.
He's not gonna be a kid forever.
Sorry, folks. We're headed
for more choppy air.
Please return to your seats,
and keep your seatbelts
securely fastened.
Hey.Hi.
What's up, beautiful?
No, no, don't get up.
I'm fine.
Ooh.
You... Look at you.
Mwah!
Welcome home. Wow, it's good to be back.
We missed you. Oh, yeah? I missed you too.
A-ten, hut! No.
Mm-mm. What?
No soldiers in this house.
Oh. Just me? Just you.
There we go. A little head.
Spine.
And heartbeat.
Dana, thank you. I love you.
I love you too.
You guys wanna know the sex?
Yes.Yes.
It's a boy. I knew it. Yes! It's a boy.
What's up, little fella?
How you doing? It's Papa.
I knew it was a boy, I knew it.
Doc, can you take a picture?
Charles. Just one.
Sure. I'm sorry.
Say, "It's a boy."
It's a boy.
There's enough money
in these accounts,
so you can withdraw
whenever you need to.
My combat pay gets deposited
on the 15th of every month.
I'm not gonna need
to spend much over there,
so it's gonna add up.
Okay?
This is a power of attorney,
so you can sign
for military dependent benefits.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah. Sure.
When people go to war,
what do they do about sex?
I don't know.
I never think about it.
I'm more worried about getting
shot than I am horny.
I was just thinking
that if you need sex in Iraq,
I mean, to help you
get through it,
I want you to know
that you have my permission.
Have you lost your mind? I'm serious.
Me too. If you need human contact
or someone to hold, Dana, stop.
Or to be held, I don't
want you... Dana, stop.
Dana, I don't want
another woman.
And I'll never disrespect you
or my son like that.
I hope you don't expect me
to extend that same offer
because you better keep
that shit locked up.
Shut up. I ain't laughing.
Okay.
I want you to keep this
some place safe.
Just in case
something happens to me.
Nothing is going
to happen to you.
I know, but I don't
want you to worry
I got you something.
About funeral arrangements
or anything like that.
What's this? It's a journal.
So you can write to your son.
Even if it's just a page or two.
Open it.
I, uh...
I don't know what to say.
What do I write?
Well, it's especially for dads,
so there's some questions
to get you started.
Tell him who you are.
What you believe in.
And tell him you love him.
Just so he knows.
Jordan, always remember,
your thoughts and actions
must be open to change
and improvement.
But your convictions
must be non-negotiable.
So live by your convictions.
And on your journey,
if you ever get down
and feel like you need
to talk to someone,
then talk to the one
who can do something about it.
Mom. Mom. Yes?
You said my dad couldn't come
home when I was born.
No, sweetie. Why not?
Ma, can you hear me?
Yeah. Yeah, I can hear you.
Hi, baby.
Hey, baby girl. How you doing?
I'm, uh... I'm good.
Hang on, hang on.
Say hi to your son.
Hey, what's up, soldier?
A-ten, hut!
Oh, he's kicking. He's kicking?
He hears you. He hears you.
Yeah, he know Daddy voice.
We miss you. I miss you too.
How are you?
Well, "gainfully employed"
would definitely be
an understatement, but...
Sorry I haven't called you.
Mm-hm. It's been three weeks.
Where are you?
I wanna look at it on my map.
You know I can't tell you that.
Thank you for my pictures,
though.
You look beautiful.
I mean, shit!
I'm loving the belly.
Yeah, it's easy for you to say.
You're not the one
who has to carry him around.
It's true, it's true.
Can't wait to meet him. You and me, both.
You know, hold him.
Which reminds me, you need
to tell me when you're coming,
so I can set a date
to be induced.
Yeah, uh... I don't know yet.
Well, you must have some idea.
Haven't you put in a request
for your leave?
No. Not yet.
Well, you're cutting it
kind of close.
What are you waiting for?
Charles?
I don't know.
You don't know what?
Charles?
Yes, ma'am.
What are you telling me?
Let's go, let's go.
Move it, come on.
You're not coming, are you?
Hello?
Ma, I just need you to please,
just try to understand.
We got in country
a couple months ago.
I can't do this without you.
My guys are not...
No, Charles, you promised me.
Things change.
But you promised me. We adapt.
That's what we do.
I'm having your baby.
I'm responsible
for an entire company.
If my men got killed while I was
gone, I wouldn't forgive myself.
That can happen
whether you are there or not.
It's not like I'm asking you
to go on a cruise.
I can't do this. Just breathe.
Charles, please.
You promised me. You know I love you.
We need you as much as they do.
I love you so much.
Give me some time. Please, Charles,
I am begging you.
Charles? I love you.
We're moving out.
I gotta go. I'll call you soon.No.
Don't get off this phone.
Charles? No, no, no. Charles? All right.
Son, I couldn't be at your
birth because of the war.
And I hope you and your mother
can forgive me.
Every time I roll out
of that gate,
I pray I don't run out of time.
Time with you,
time with your mother.
So much to do, Jordan.
But I have faith
that you are safe and sound.
Because you're surrounded
by strong women.
These are your first teachers,
little prince.
And all of these women
embody the reasons you should
never, ever disrespect
or lay your hand
against any woman.
The woman you choose
to be your partner
should guard
your friendship first, son.
You're doing good, good!
Company, attention!
And just like you,
she should be honorable.
And take pride
in how she carries herself.
But remember...
Here we go! Here we go, push!
Beauty is in the eye
of the beholder.
Roll call!
And real beauty
comes from deep inside.
He's here. He's coming, he's coming!
PFC Coats!
Here, first sergeant!
Private Bryant! Here, first sergeant!
Just take one look
at your mother,
and that'll tell you
what I think beautiful is.
Corporal Light!
Corporal Robbie Light!
Corporal Robbie Glen Light!
Welcome home, Daddy.
Come meet your son.
Hey. Hey.
Oh, my God.
Hey. Hi.
Hi.
This boy is so special. It's okay.
You gonna be a blessing
to everybody you meet.
I know, Daddy's home.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Someone else thought
I was his nanny today.
He's so light-skinned,
no one thinks he's mine.
He just gets that from my mom.
So you know what I did? What?
I pulled out my boob
and I breastfed him right there,
in front of her.
Lucky I didn't squirt milk
on her little punk ass.
Guess I gotta get you a ring,
then.
Man, white people,
they won't think twice.
Are you all right? Yeah.
It's just asthma.
Since when do you have asthma?
Our base is by a power plant.
Doc said I probably got it
there. It's nothing.
Are you sure? Yes.
Don't worry about it.
But I'm serious, though.
I can get you a ring.
We could do the whole thing
while I'm in town.
What whole thing?
Jordan could be my best man,
we can get him a little tux.
You mean get married. Why not?
No. I don't wanna cram
our whole lives into one visit.
I want a real wedding.
With white calla lilies,
and flower girls
in tulle dresses.
What kind of dresses? Tulle.
And look,
you've got six weeks left.
I can wait.
Then so can I.
Charles? Yeah?
Hey, we got a surprise for you.
Oh, no, you don't.Mm-hm.
We have enough soldiers
in the family.
All right, fine.
I'll wait till he's 18,
and take him down
to the recruiters.
But in the meantime, Comfy.
Put this on. What is this?
Just trust us. Go.
Where are we?
I know we're in the East Side.
And I know we're in the park.
Oh, my God.
Why are you doing this?
You're so loud. Charles.
Be quiet!
All right, you can take it off.
Thank you.
Olive oil. Extra virgin.
Just like you...
used to be. Shut up.
Peek-a-boo! Peek-a-boo!
He's just a biscuit,
I just wanna eat him up.
What's up, little soldier?
What's going on?
Can I get a membership
into your little boys' club?
I don't know, biscuit,
what do you say?
Should we let her in our club?
Hmm?
What's that?
He said
your application's pending.
Pending? He calls the shots.
As much as I whip my boobies
out to feed him?
That's a good point.
Hold, please.
You sure? I don't know.
She's good looking.
All right. Okay, okay, fine.
On account of the booby thing,
he said okay.
Biscuit. Biscuit.
Sweetie, you okay?
Charles.
Ain't that right, biscuit?
Everything's good.
My little man.
I don't want this one.
Which one?
Is this you?
How about this one?
I don't want this one either.
Can't you just go AWOL
and stay here with us?
So you wanna marry a coward?
All right, fine, go.
You hear that, biscuit?
She doesn't like Daddy's work.
Love you.
Take care of your mother for me.
And you...
You still gonna marry me
when I get back home?
I can't wait.
Can I pick out my own tux?
I want you to wear
your dress blues.
I'm marrying a soldier.
Yeah, you are.
I love you. I love you more.
Guess what.
Oh, God, don't start.
Guess what.No.
Say it.
Chicken butt.
Crazy woman.
See you, biscuit.
Take care of my girl. I will.
All right?
You know, technically,
he didn't free the slaves.
They freed themselves.
Did they?
The Emancipation Proclamation
only applied
to Confederate states,
but it also allowed Black people
to join the Army
and help win the war.
Someone's been paying attention
in history class.
How did my dad die?
I told you, baby.
All you said
was that a bomb exploded.
I wanna know what happened.
Your father was a part
of the First Battalion
67th Armed Regiment
from Fort Hood, Texas.
They called themselves
the Death Dealers.
Which was fitting
because most of their missions
in Iraq
took part in a place
the military called
"the Triangle of Death."
Your dad's nickname was Top,
because of his rank.
He was in charge of 105 men
of Charlie Company.
Their nickname
was the Carnivores.
Your dad's job was, and I quote:
"to teach them to stay alive
and kill the enemy."
On October 14th, 2006,
he took them on a mission.
He could've stayed behind
that day.
He even let
his battle buddies sleep in.
But your dad
would never ask his soldiers
to do anything
he wouldn't do himself.
He went where they went.
Let's move out.
That's the kind of man
your dad was.
It's go time, Imhoff. Cherry, let him know.
Load up!
We trust in you, oh, God.
We trust in you in the name
of the Father and the Son,
in the name of Jesus Christ.
Amen.
Their mission was to re-supply
a place called the Island.
It was an isolated spot
where about 60 soldiers
were posted.
At38 in the morning,
their convoy passed a place
called Jurf Al Sakhar.
It was about two miles
from the Island.
- IED! IED!- Return fire!
Light it up! Light it up!
Imhoff! Drop, drop down. Cover the rear!
Cover the rear!
Return fire!
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Come on, Imhoff.
Soldier down. Need help. Help!
Move it, move it!
Top! I got you, Top!
I got you. Come on. Come on.
Medic!
It's gonna be all right.
I got you, Top.
Slow your breath. Come on.
I got you, bro.
Come on. Look at me.
Medic! Medic!
Come on. Stay with me.
Stay with me.
Come on, stay with me,
I got you.
Come on. Stay with me.
Stay with me, bro.
No! No, no, no!
Stay with me, Top.
I'm right here. Stay with me.
Medic!
Stay with me! Medic!
Hello?
Uh, I'm good.
How are you?
Yeah. A couple of friends just
walked in. What's going on?
Wait. I'm sorry, what happened?
He didn't... He didn't make...
No. No, no, no. Where is he?
No, where is he? Tell me!
Where is he?
No! No!
No.
No, no.
No!
They had a plan in place.
A secret plan, in case something
happened to your father.
He didn't want me to be alone
when I heard he was gone.
Why were we even fighting
that war?
Well, that depends
on who you ask.
Some might say we were fighting
to free a country
from a tyrant
and stop terrorists.
Others might say we're the
reason they became terrorists
in the first place.
But I bet
if you asked your father,
he'd say he was fighting
for his soldiers.
To keep them alive
and to get them home.
But he had to die to do it?
Well, that's what heroes do,
baby.
Jordan, what are you doing?
Working out.
My dad said physical fitness
is important.
I've only got one body.
I better take care of it.
It's working, isn't it?
I'm gonna go hit the showers
and get dressed.
Maybe we should wait.
Till the rain lets up.
No, we've gotta go this morning.
Get dressed.
You brought your suit?
Let's move out.
Mom. You all right?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Told you the sun
would come out today.
Let's go.
What is this? I sent an e-mail.
It went a little viral.
More people wanted to come,
but they couldn't make it.
Jordan, why didn't you just ask me?
Mom.
Hi, baby.Hi.
How are you, pumpkin?
Oh, my God, I can't believe
you guys are here.
Hi.
You helped him with this?
He wanted to surprise you.
It worked.
Excuse me, everybody?
Can I have your attention?
Mom.
Thank you all for coming.
Some of you
came from pretty far.
I'd like to read this.
It's from my dad.
"Family means everything,
Jordan."
It's why I wake up
in the morning.
It's why I put on the uniform
and risk my life.
And the great thing about family
is that when you get older,
"you get to choose who's in it."
He underlined the word "you."
"So choose wisely."
Surround yourself with people
that love you for you
and love them back.
Because love is the one thing
in this world
"that's worth fighting for."
So I guess that makes
all of you my family.
Mom.
Since you never got a flag,
my dad would want me
to make sure you got one.
Private Imhoff,
Private Mohammed.
On behalf of a grateful nation
and Charlie Company,
we wouldn't be here
if it weren't for Top.
None of us would, ma'am.
This belongs to you.
Dear Jordan,
when your father died,
I thought my life was over.
But the truth is,
it was just beginning.
You and your dad both showed me
how beautiful life is
when you live it below
your neck and in your heart.
Risky place, the heart.
Because it's fragile,
so it breaks.
And it hurts.
After your dad left, I tried
my best to feel nothing
so my heart
would never break again.
But even pain
is better than nothing.
Because without pain,
it's impossible to find joy.
I hope these words
will help you understand
the remarkable love
your father and I shared.
I want you to have
that kind of love, Jordan.
The kind of love
that does not ask her
to be anyone
other than who she is.
And that does not ask
any more of you.
Dear heavenly Father,
thank you for bringing
us here as family
to honor the life
and remember the life
of Charles Monroe King.
My prayer for you, Jordan,
is that you carry with you
the knowledge
that you will always have
two parents guiding you.
But my mother's intuition alone
will not be enough
to teach you to be a man.
For that, I give you
your father's journal.
And the wisdom it contains.
Its pages should give you
an idea of where you came from
so you can decide
on exactly where you're going.
I love you, son.
Always and forever.
Mom.